Guide to the Ann Schoenfeld collection on the Fulton Ferry Landing Association 2019.009
Brooklyn Historical Society
Ann Schoenfeld collection on the Fulton Ferry Landing Association
1997-2001
1977-2005
Brooklyn Historical Society
Schoenfeld, Ann
2019.009
0.63 Linear Feet in one full and one half manuscript box.
The Fulton Ferry Landing Association was formed in 1988 by residents of the Fulton Ferry Landing Historic District. The collection documents development in the neighborhood from the 1980s through the early 2000s, in particular by Two Trees Management; transportation issues including traffic and ferries; the development of Brooklyn Bridge Park; and Creative Time's Art in the Anchorage program.
Scope and Contents
The bulk of this small collection pertains to the work and advocacy of the Fulton Ferry Landing Association. Topics represented include the construction of Brooklyn Bridge Park, traffic in downtown Brooklyn and a proposed water taxi, Creative Time's Art in the Anchorage program, and development proposals from Two Trees Management. The collection also includes Fulton Ferry Landing Association administrative documents, event announcements, meeting agendas and minutes, and issues of the newsletter Currents. Other neighborhood organizations in the area are also represented, including the Brooklyn Heights Association and the Old Brooklyn Waterfront Alliance.
Biographical / Historical
Ann Schoenfeld has been a resident of the Fulton Ferry Historic District since the 1980s. She was active in the Fulton Ferry Landing Association, a neighborhood association founded in 1988. Ann Schoenfeld was the graphic designer for the association's short-lived newsletter, Currents, which was published for several years in the late 1990s. The Fulton Ferry Landing Association remains active as of 2021, with a focus on development and transportation issues affecting the neighborhood.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open to research.
Related Materials
Back to the City collection (1991.036)
Bedford-Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation publication and photograph collection, 1968–2007 (ARC.124)
Brooklyn Chamber of Commerce publications (ARC.165)
Brooklyn neighborhood associations and civic organizations publications (ARC.167)
Downtown Brooklyn Development Association records (1979.021)
Eastern Parkway Coalition records (2007.016)
Ron Shiffman collection on the Pratt Center for Community Development (2013.023)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Ann Schoenfeld in 2019.
DUMBO Historic District (New York, N.Y.); Fulton Ferry Landing (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn Bridge Park (New York, N.Y.); Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Neighborhood Associations; Schoenfeld, Ann
- Brooklyn Bridge Park, 1997-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Brooklyn Heights Association, 1988-1989, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Community Based Plan for the Old Brooklyn District, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Community Board Two, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Creative Times Arts in the Anchorage, 1983-1989, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Currents Newsletter Distribution Lists, circa 1997-2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Downtown Brooklyn Traffic, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Eagle Tenants Corporation, 1989, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Fulton Ferry Historic District Designation, 1977-1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Fulton Ferry Landing Association, 1995-2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Fulton Ferry Landing Association Events Announcements, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Fulton Ferry Landing Association Meeting Agendas, 1997-2000, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Fulton Ferry News, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Landmarks Preservation Commission, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous, 1982-1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Old Brooklyn Waterfront Alliance, 1997-1999 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Photographs, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Purchase Building, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- New York Water Taxi LLC, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Two Trees Management, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 7)